Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 19.
We are asked to find the time complexity of this function.
It's called there two parameters A and B, and we are going to calculate that division.
So we start before.
Before we start, please try to post the video and try to solve this exercise by your own on paper and
commend your answer.
And that's all in the comments below.
Waiting your questions and answers.
OK, so let's begin we start in count equal to zero, this declaration is of one in sum, equal to be
of one.
OK, so this loop, while some less than or equal to a we are getting some less than or equal to a sum
equal to the old sum.
Plus B, this declaration is equal to all four.
And count, we are increasing one by one.
So we are going to go through the values from B because some equal to B to A or less than A.
So this func this slope will go through.
All elements, because plus blood count would be plus plus firearms, you OK?
Be equal to some.
OK, so we are going to go through from B to A and through all the elements.
OK.
And return count, but there is something.
Here, some is equal to the old, some plus B.
OK, so the sum is going to be multiplied by a like or the B plus some.
OK.
If you don't understand, let's go and get it.
Take an example here, let me show you.
Dave, and let me take a look.
Hey, where is the cursor?
Cursor.
A equals two then and B equal to.
Do.
And count equal to zero, so count is equal now to zero count equal to zero.
And some is equal to be equal to do so, while some less than or equal to a sum less than 10.
Yes.
So go and execute.
This sum now is equal to the old some.
Plus, B some it is two plus B is too, so sum is equal to four.
Now, increase count by one zero, it would become one again, some less than or equal to two and less
than or equal 10.
Yes, because some equal to four.
So it is less than 10 or equal then.
The old sum is equal to the new sum, which is sort of the new sum is equal to the old sandwiches for
plus to be equal to two, it is equal to six count.
Is increased by one, it is becoming, too.
Now some is equal to six, going up six less than or equal to 10.
Yes, go and again and some in the news, some is equal to six plus two is equal to a count.
Equal to Serena, going up, some is equal to eight less than or equal to 10.
Yes.
So some.
Now, some.
The new sum equal to eight plus two equals to 10 go account.
See what the for going up.
Some less than or equal then some is 10 less than or equal.
10.
Yes.
So go and execute.
This sum is equal to 10 plus two equal to 12, so count increase it by one equal to five.
Going up some is 12 less than or equal.
10 No.
So go and stop here.
Return the count count we have five.
OK.
Now, what is the time complexity?
Think about it.
We have divided then over be.
Which is true.
And we have made five iterations.
If we took a equals to 12, we will make six iterations, OK?
According to 12 and be equal to two.
It will result in six.
If we took a equal to 14 and be equal to do, it would result in seven.
So please try to find the sequence.
As I told you, time complex these questions is related to the examples that you took.
So always took an example to see and solve that algorithm at bat.
So when a equal to 10 B is equal and to.
Be to let me try to put here a B and the result.
Of how many counts?
Five.
When we have 12 and be able to do it will result in six counts, 14 and due to a result seven.
So we have noticed that a over B will result in the count.
Therefore, that time complexity of this question is oh of a of a b.
So always there.
When you think about complexity, time, complexity, they can take more than an example and try to
find their sequence that this algorithm follows.
So this pattern is dividing a over B.